LINDA OYAPI ASAMOAH

LinkedIn | (443) 985-4591 | oyapiasamoah@gmail.com

SUMMARY STATEMENT

Certified AWS Solutions Architect with experience in terraform, Linux, and bash scripting. Skilled in designing and implementing solutions across Linux, Windows, and cloud platforms. Committed to ongoing professional development and staying up-to-date on the latest industry trends and best practices.

EDUCATION

University of Ghana (UG)

08/2019 - 12/2020

Master's in Public Health

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect-Associate

12/2021

TECHNICAL SKILLS

AWS | Azure | Windows | Linux | Terraform | Ansible | Bash Scripting | MySQL

WORK EXPERIENCE

Linux/Cloud Engineer, Quest Logic Solutions

10/2022 – Present

- Migrating on-prem Active Directory 2012 to Active Directory 2019
- Experience joining Linux and Windows OS to Active Directory
- Build dev environment using Terraform script to deploy (Virtual Network, Security Groups, RBAC, Subnet, Public IP) to Azure Cloud
- Create documentation, user guides, diagrams and SOPs as needed
- Writing shell scripts for various tasks such as back-ups, collecting logs, installation, and monitoring
- Configure and administer Nagios monitoring tools for server monitoring and incident alerts

Cloud DevOps Engineer, Canditude

02/2022 - 10/2022

- Designed, deployed, and monitored cloud-based infrastructure for clients using Terraform
- Improved client incident management lifecycle to identify, mitigate, and learn from reliability risks
- Researched to develop new skills with unfamiliar tools and technologies for quick and effective adoption
- Worked on AWS CI/CD pipeline jobs for end-to-end automation to commit, build, test, and troubleshoot issues during the build process
- Shadow senior engineers for continuous improvement and knowledge transfer

Cloud Technology Trainer, GetINNOtized GmbH

08/2021 - 07/2022

- Developed and coordinated training sessions to help individuals learn AWS Services and Best Practices
- Identified areas of concern uncovered during training sessions and suggested methods to solve them
- Assisted students to navigate and understand cloud services via Teams, Outlook, and phone
- Categorized all existing AWS Resources